Article Name,NER Name Extracted
2020s_wildfire_season_is_historic_charring_more__Colorado_Sun_The_CO___October_26_2020.txt,"('Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Utah State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rockies', 'LOCATION'), ('Bridget Kochel', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Parks and Wildlife', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Noel Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Livingston', 'PERSON')"
20_years_of_planning_saved_Rocky_Mountain_National__Colorado_Sun_The_CO___June_20_2021.txt,"('Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Fern Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Lewelling', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Green Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Beaver Meadows', 'PERSON'), ('Trail Ridge Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron', 'PERSON'), ('Mike Lewelling', 'PERSON'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Booth Early', 'PERSON'), ('Glen Haven', 'LOCATION'), ('Cub Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Mount Wuh', 'LOCATION'), ('Buthe', 'PERSON'), ('Never Summer Range', 'LOCATION'), ('Forest Canyon Overlook on Trail Ridge Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Bear Lake Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Rockies', 'LOCATION'), ('Koren Nydick', 'PERSON'), ('Old Fall River Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Instagram', 'LOCATION'), ('Beaver Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Doug', 'PERSON'), ('Spruce Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Nydick', 'PERSON'), ('Lewelling', 'LOCATION'), ('Darla Sidles', 'PERSON'), ('Youth Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beaver Meadows', 'LOCATION'), ('Bear Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Upper Beaver Meadows Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Moraine Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('Parker', 'PERSON'), ('Onahu Lodge', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kawuneeche', 'LOCATION'), ('Fern Lake', 'PERSON'), ('Corral Creek Trailhead Bridge', 'LOCATION'), ('Switzerland', 'LOCATION'), ('Great Smoky Mountains National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Doug Parker', 'PERSON'), ('Sprague Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('YMCA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain', 'LOCATION')"
416_Fire_turned_out_to_be_a_healthy_burn_for_the__Journal_The_Cortez_Dolores_Mancos_CO___August_28_2020.txt,"('Mountain Studies Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Missionary Ridge Fire', 'LOCATION'), ('Southwest Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Rapid Gambel', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fort Lewis College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('William Baker', 'PERSON'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jerry McBrideDurango Herald', 'PERSON'), ('Michael Remke', 'PERSON'), ('Jo', 'PERSON'), ('Seth Bogle', 'PERSON'), ('Baker', 'PERSON'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Remke', 'PERSON'), ('Julie Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Mancos', 'LOCATION'), ('University of Wyoming', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hurricane Bud', 'PERSON'), ('Jonina Vanderbilt', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOCATION'), ('Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Manco', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jonathan Romeo', 'PERSON'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION'), ('Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Pacific Ocean', 'LOCATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Hermosa Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Gambel', 'PERSON'), ('Bud', 'PERSON'), ('Dolores', 'PERSON'), ('west coast of Mexico', 'LOCATION')"
A - Act_now_to_guard_against_wildfire__Montrose_Daily_Press_The_CO___May_4_2020.txt,"('WRWC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jamie Gomez', 'PERSON'), ('Montrose Daily Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West Region Wildfire Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mo', 'PERSON'), ('Katharhynn Heidelberg', 'LOCATION'), ('Daniel Beveridge', 'PERSON'), ('Southwest', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Insurance Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Project Wildfire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Fire Protection Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gunnison County', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Association of Realtors', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gomez', 'PERSON')"
A - Allenspark firefighters get needed equipment.txt,"('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Cousineau', 'PERSON'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Area Club', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leo Touzjian', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Johnathon Oppermann', 'PERSON'), ('Durstine', 'PERSON'), ('Allenspark Fire Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer', 'LOCATION'), ('Allenspark Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Counties', 'LOCATION'), ('Tamara Durstine', 'PERSON'), ('Couseineau', 'PERSON'), ('Northern Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Oppermann', 'PERSON'), ('Pinewood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION')"
A - Analyzing data on the Crystal River near Redstone he calcula.txt,"('Lukas', 'PERSON'), ('Swift Communications', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jake DeWolfe', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Marble', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Journalism', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Mo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Osenga', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lake Powell', 'LOCATION'), ('Redstone', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Global Change Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Crystal River', 'LOCATION'), ('Elise Osenga', 'PERSON'), ('Carbondale', 'LOCATION')"
A - An_unexpected_variable_Experimental_Forest_digs__Sky-Hi_News_Granby_CO___August_21_2020.txt,"('Elder', 'PERSON'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('County Road 73', 'LOCATION'), ('Kelly Elder', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Deadhorse Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Starr', 'PERSON')"
A - Black_Forest_residents_express_concerns_about_new__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___April_18_2021.txt,"('Black Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('El Paso County', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Forest Preservation Plan', 'LOCATION'), ('Gebhart', 'PERSON'), ('Stokka', 'PERSON'), ('Cathedral Pines', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Pines', 'LOCATION'), ('Stokka', 'LOCATION'), ('El Paso County Planning', 'LOCATION'), ('Mark Gebhart', 'PERSON'), ('Craig Dossey', 'PERSON'), ('Black Forest Preservation Plan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dossey', 'PERSON'), ('Houseal-Lavigne Associates', 'ORGANIZATION')"
A - Cameron_Peak_fire_resulted_in_a_market_loss_of__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___January_14_2021.txt,"('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Parks', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Angelique Curtis', 'PERSON'), (""Larimer County Assessor 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Curtis', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Arapahoe', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Chambers Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Long Draw', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Mullen', 'PERSON'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bob Overbeck', 'PERSON'), ('Laramie River Valley', 'LOCATION')"
A - City of Durango invites comments on sustainability plan  Ini.txt,"('Virtual City Hall', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Imogen Ainsworth', 'PERSON'), ('BLM', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trump Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Outdoor Industry Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('North Fork', 'LOCATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Energy Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paonia Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('North Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Jumbo Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('Gunnison River', 'LOCATION'), ('Sarah Kelly', 'PERSON')"
A voice for the unheard Activists bring the impact to.txt,"('Tafoya', 'PERSON'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Midwest', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Environmental Protection Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elyria-Swansea', 'LOCATION'), ('PUC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('EJSCREEN', 'LOCATION'), ('EPA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aurora', 'LOCATION'), ('Xcel Energy-Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Xcel Energy-Colorado', 'PERSON'), ('Elyria', 'LOCATION'), ('Judith Kohler Judith Kohler', 'PERSON'), ('Alice Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('JudithKohler Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Public Utilities Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ean Tafoya', 'PERSON'), ('Swansea', 'LOCATION'), ('Ren-Caspar Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Environmental Justice Coalition on Black Hills Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('GreenLatinos', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dominique Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Comanche', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('Sierra Club', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judith Kohler', 'PERSON'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Denver Environmental Health', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado General Assembly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pueblo', 'LOCATION'), ('Xcel', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver Post', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Advocates say financial analysis shows Boulder muni would re.txt,"('Burchell', 'PERSON'), ('Deborah Swearingen', 'PERSON'), ('Peterson', 'PERSON'), ('Yates', 'PERSON'), ('Bob Yates', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Emily Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('Susan Peterson', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Public Service Company of Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alison Burchell', 'PERSON'), ('Elizabeth Hartman', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leslie Glustrom', 'PERSON')"
After_the_beetles_Forests_starting_to_recover__Post_Independent_Glenwood_Springs_CO___February_24_2020.txt,"('Ecological Society of America', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sarah Hart', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Veblen', 'PERSON'), ('University of Colorado Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University of Wisconsin Madison', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Robert Andrus', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Fire Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cada', 'PERSON'), ('Camp Fire', 'LOCATION'), ('Thomas Veblen', 'PERSON'), ('Hart', 'PERSON'), ('Paul Cada', 'PERSON'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Andrus', 'PERSON'), ('Vail', 'LOCATION')"
After_the_fire__Delta_County_Independent_CO___December_11_2020.txt,"('Mark Rackay Mother Nature', 'PERSON'), ('Mark Rackay', 'PERSON'), ('Nucla', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Flamingo', 'LOCATION'), ('Mesa County', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Uncompahgre National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Western Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Forest of Mangroves', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ma Nature', 'PERSON'), ('Everglades National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Florida Bay', 'LOCATION')"
All-electric_is_the_way_to_go_Writers_on_the__Tribune_The_Gleneagle_Black_Forest_CO___January_26_2021.txt,"('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Nevada', 'LOCATION'), ('Tribune', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('San Francisco', 'LOCATION'), ('AUDEN SCHENDLER', 'PERSON'), ('Snowmass Village', 'LOCATION'), ('Board of Supervisors', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Og', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Basalt', 'LOCATION'), ('Garry Kasparov', 'PERSON'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('Seattle', 'LOCATION'), ('East West Partners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('T ed White', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Electric Pass Lodge', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Auden Schendler', 'PERSON'), ('United States', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Skiing Company', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Allenspark_firefighters_get_needed_equipment__Estes_Park_Trail-Gazette_CO___May_27_2021.txt,"('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Cousineau', 'PERSON'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Area Club', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leo Touzjian', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Johnathon Oppermann', 'PERSON'), ('Durstine', 'PERSON'), ('Allenspark Fire Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer', 'LOCATION'), ('Allenspark Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Counties', 'LOCATION'), ('amara Durstine', 'PERSON'), ('Couseineau', 'PERSON'), ('Northern Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Oppermann', 'PERSON'), ('Pinewood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Wendy Rig', 'PERSON')"
All_public_lands_close_in_Clear_Creek_County__Clear_Creek_Courant_Idaho_Springs_CO___October_20_2020.txt,"('Clear Creek County', 'LOCATION'), ('Haas', 'PERSON'), ('Clear Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Clear Creek Road & Bridge', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Arapaho & Roosevelt National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bergen Peak', 'LOCATION'), ('Virginia Canyon Mountain Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Wheelock', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Parks & Wildlife', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Randy Wheelock', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Evans State Wildlife Areas', 'LOCATION'), ('Georgetown Loop Railroad', 'LOCATION'), ('Georgetown', 'LOCATION'), ('USFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Idaho Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Scott Haas', 'PERSON'), ('Historic District Public Lands', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver Mountain Parks', 'LOCATION'), (""Clear Creek Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION')"
An Earth Day Report Card for Aspen  the Roaring Fork Valley.txt,"('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Points Film Fest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('US Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Scott Condon', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Hunter Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Bailey McDonough', 'PERSON'), ('Crystal Lake trailhead', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('RFTA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Doyle', 'PERSON'), ('Pitkin County Open Space and Trails', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Basalt Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Braderich Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Mountain Bike Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen Valley Land Trust', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Kinsley', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Maroon Bells', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Karin Teague', 'PERSON'), ('Holy Cross Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dwight Shellman', 'PERSON'), ('Holy Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paepcke Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Cottonwood Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Lisa Stoeffler', 'PERSON'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Snowmass Village', 'LOCATION'), ('Kelsey BrunnerThe Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Basalt', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Mo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Edwards', 'PERSON'), ('Ski Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Will Roush', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Center for Environmental Studies', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pitkin County Healthy Rivers', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('US Forest Service Aspen Country Day School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Highland Peak', 'LOCATION'), ('Independence Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Pitkin County', 'LOCATION'), ('Sofia Abbaszadeh', 'PERSON'), ('AUDEN', 'PERSON'), ('Devil', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('JOHN DOYLE Aspen', 'PERSON'), ('Shoshone Dam', 'LOCATION'), ('USFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Community Office for Resource Efficiency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mona Newton', 'PERSON'), ('Independence Pass Foundation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wilderness Workshop Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Times Weekly Section', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('TACAW', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nell Lieb', 'PERSON'), ('Habitat for Humanity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('KARIN TEAGUE', 'PERSON'), ('Andrew Lussie', 'PERSON'), ('Electric Pass Lodge', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Defiende Nuestra Tierra', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Auden Schendler', 'PERSON'), ('Thompson Divide', 'LOCATION'), ('Voces Unidas de las Montaas', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mother Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('Maroon Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Skiing Company', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Anatomy_of_a_wildfire_How_fuel_sources_weather__Vail_Daily_CO___August_19_2020.txt,"('Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Summit Fire & EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Torben Grumstrup', 'PERSON'), ('Fire Sciences Laboratory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Missoula', 'LOCATION'), ('Grumstrup', 'PERSON'), ('Jeff Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Ho', 'PERSON'), ('Greater Eagle Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wilmore', 'PERSON'), ('Montana', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Ross Wilmore', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United States', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'ORGANIZATION')"
As Colorado wildfires burn fears that climate change is caus.txt,"('Fischer', 'PERSON'), ('Denver Water', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mike Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Bro', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Natural Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Southwest', 'LOCATION'), ('Richmond', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('Clay Clarke', 'PERSON'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Environmental Defense Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Scott Denning', 'PERSON'), ('The Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lester', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Udall', 'PERSON'), ('Putnam', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jeff Lukas', 'PERSON'), ('Russ Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Portland', 'LOCATION'), ('John Putnam', 'PERSON'), ('Renee Chacon', 'PERSON'), ('Lake Mead', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Water Conservation Board', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pine Gulch', 'PERSON'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado River Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Energy Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dan Gibbs', 'PERSON'), ('Broomfield Enterprise', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bruce Finley', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado River Basin State', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grace Rink', 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Gibbs', 'PERSON'), ('NASA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pueblo', 'LOCATION'), ('CSU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Will Toor', 'PERSON'), ('Emily Fischer', 'PERSON'), ('Denver Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brad Udall', 'PERSON')"
"As San Luis Valley's water squeeze intensifies, Gov. Jared Polis.txt","('Cleave Simpson', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Sangre de Cristo', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Simpson', 'PERSON'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Bill Owens', 'PERSON'), ('Oakes', 'PERSON'), ('Dion Oakes', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Quinoa', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Tyler Mitchell', 'PERSON'), ('Kate Greenberg', 'PERSON'), ('San Luis Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Paris', 'LOCATION'), ('Jim Erlich', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Brendon Rockey', 'PERSON'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), ('Greenberg', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern Plains', 'LOCATION'), ('Brendon', 'PERSON'), ('Renewable Water Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sangre de Cristos', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Rio Grande Water Conservation District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('Patagonia', 'LOCATION'), ('China', 'LOCATION'), ('Rio Grande River', 'LOCATION'), ('Poncha Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Rio Grande', 'LOCATION'), ('Sheldon Rockey', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'LOCATION')"
Ash raining down on Colorado a sign of hotter drier and more.txt,"('Mike Ferris', 'PERSON'), ('Phillip', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('High Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Lewis College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ponderosa', 'PERSON'), ('Bill Owen', 'PERSON'), ('Alison Robb', 'PERSON'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Mesa University and Western Colorado Community College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Missionary Ridge', 'LOCATION'), ('CSFS Wildfire Mitigation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Russ Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Julie Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Daniel Beveridge', 'PERSON'), ('Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Pine Gulch', 'PERSON'), ('Robb', 'PERSON'), ('Battaglia', 'PERSON'), ('Mary Shinn', 'PERSON'), ('Gambel', 'PERSON'), ('Mike Battaglia', 'PERSON'), ('Dennis Phillip', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Western Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Wildland Fire Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Spring Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Research Station', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Interagency Fire Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Aspen environmentalists reenergized with Biden taking office.txt,"('Colorado River Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Ecoflight', 'PERSON'), ('Camp Hale', 'LOCATION'), ('Deb Haaland', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('BLM', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Rifle Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Regan', 'PERSON'), ('Congressional', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roush', 'PERSON'), ('EPA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Brian Deese', 'PERSON'), ('Grant Stevens', 'PERSON'), ('Boebert', 'PERSON'), ('McCarthy', 'PERSON'), ('Carbondale', 'LOCATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Lane', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Interior', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chris Lane', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'LOCATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('Thompson', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Skiing Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bruce Gordon', 'PERSON'), ('Wilderness Workshop', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Scott CondonThe Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Environmental Protection Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thompson Divide', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thompson Divide', 'PERSON'), ('NRA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Will Roush', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Center for Environmental Studies', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Lauren Boebert', 'PERSON'), ('Gordon', 'PERSON'), ('Latina', 'LOCATION'), ('Joseph Biden', 'PERSON'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cecilia Martinez', 'PERSON'), ('China', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Bear Ears National Monument', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('North Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Roan Plateau', 'LOCATION'), ('Gunnison National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Auden Schendler', 'PERSON'), ('Skico', 'PERSON'), ('Thompson Divide', 'LOCATION'), ('National Economic Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('Gina McCarthy', 'PERSON'), ('Scott Tipton', 'PERSON'), ('Schendler', 'PERSON')"
Aspen Fire strategizes for the future.txt,"('Aspen Ambulance District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('ESCI Consulting Inc.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rick Balentine', 'PERSON'), ('EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sacramento', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Balentine', 'PERSON'), ('Jake Andersen', 'PERSON'), ('Andersen', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Ambulance District', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Ambulance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('AP Triton', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Aspen officials elect to divest from fossil fueldriven corpo.txt,"('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Exxon Mobil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Torre', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Wells Fargo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Berkshire Hathaway', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('City Finance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pete Strecker', 'PERSON'), ('Roaring Fork', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Will Hodges', 'PERSON'), ('Berkshire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Skippy Mesirow', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Strecker', 'PERSON'), ('Rachel Richards', 'PERSON'), ('Ward Hauenstein', 'PERSON'), ('Chevron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hodges', 'PERSON')"
Aspen Skiing Co donates 60000 to elect climate leaders in 20.txt,"('Alterra', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nevada', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('The Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Rifle Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congressional', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Maine', 'LOCATION'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('Michael Fortney', 'PERSON'), ('Michigan', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Alterra Mountain Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('New Hampshire', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Skiing Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cortez', 'LOCATION'), ('Flake', 'PERSON'), ('Action Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('POW Action Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Ski Areas Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Perry', 'PERSON'), ('Alterra Mountain Company', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mario Molina', 'PERSON'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Ikon Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Powdr Corp.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('D.C.', 'LOCATION'), ('Skico', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('3rd Congressional District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Molina', 'PERSON'), ('Auden Schendler', 'PERSON'), ('Skico', 'PERSON'), ('Scott Tipton', 'PERSON'), ('North Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('Schendler', 'PERSON'), ('Tipton', 'PERSON')"
Aspen-area_fire_officials_bank_on_rain_to_ease__Aspen_Times_The_CO___July_14_2020.txt,"('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Scott Thompson', 'PERSON'), ('Colton', 'PERSON'), ('Gulf of Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'LOCATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brush Creek Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Lake Christine Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Pacific Northwest', 'LOCATION'), ('Sky Mountain Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Thompson', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Global Change Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roaring Fork Fire Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Basalt', 'LOCATION'), ('Maroon Creek Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('NWS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pitkin County', 'LOCATION'), ('Spring Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Water Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Garfield', 'LOCATION'), ('Richmond Ridge Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Jeff Colton', 'PERSON'), ('Pitkin', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elise Osenga', 'PERSON')"
Aspens building code headed toward net zero.txt,"('Bonnie Muhigirwa', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Ann Mullins', 'PERSON'), ('Skippy Mesirow', 'PERSON'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ward Hauenstein', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Holy Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mesirow', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thompson', 'PERSON'), ('Nick Thompson', 'PERSON')"
As_a_sign_that_the_Cameron_Peak_Fire_is_fading___Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___November_9_2020.txt,"('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Steve Ippoliti', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('North', 'PERSON'), ('Roosevelt National Forests', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Monte Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('North Fork Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Ippoliti', 'PERSON'), ('Steve North', 'PERSON'), ('Northwest Incident Management Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION')"
As_Cameron_Peak_Fire_work_shifts_to_repair_mode___Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___November_15_2020.txt,"('Jackie Hutchins Snow', 'PERSON'), ('Al Lawson', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('North', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Lawson', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Shawnee Hinman', 'PERSON'), ('Pacific Northwest Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('COVID-19 Lawson', 'PERSON'), ('Steve North', 'PERSON'), ('Hinman', 'PERSON')"
As_Colorados_pine_beetle_fades_whats_next_for__Durango_Herald_The_CO___June_4_2021.txt,"(""Colorado State University 's Colorado Forest Restoration Institute"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Sitton', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Mesa', 'LOCATION'), ('Tim Kyllo', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Gunnison', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Brett Wolk', 'PERSON'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Engelmann', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Wall Wood', 'LOCATION'), ('Pitts', 'PERSON'), ('Kyllo', 'PERSON'), ('Sitton', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Montrose Forest Products', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Molly Pitts', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado T imber Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dolores', 'PERSON'), ('Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('Rio Grande', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Wall Wood', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Montrose', 'LOCATION')"
As_containment_approaches_50_percent_Grizzly__Vail_Daily_CO___August_26_2020.txt,"('Great Basin Incident Management Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest Deputy Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Lisa Stoeffler', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kris Sanders', 'PERSON'), ('Stoeffler', 'PERSON'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('Tom Kurth', 'PERSON'), ('Jeff Surber', 'PERSON'), ('Kurth', 'PERSON'), ('Surber', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alaska Interagency Incident Management Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Great Basin', 'LOCATION')"
As_firefighters_make_progress_East_Troublesome__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_23_2020.txt,"('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), (""Grand County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Mullen', 'PERSON'), ('Dan Dallas', 'PERSON'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Safety', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Quinones', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lyle Hileman', 'PERSON'), ('Shroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Brett Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Scott Headrick', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Marylin', 'PERSON'), ('Stan Hilkey', 'PERSON'), ('Noel Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Quinones', 'PERSON'), ('Headrick', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain Metropolitan Airport', 'LOCATION'), ('Dallas', 'LOCATION'), ('Broomfield', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('The Denver Gazette', 'ORGANIZATION')"
As_flames_recede_dangers_remain_from_Grizzly__Eagle_Valley_Enterprise_CO___August_29_2020.txt,"('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('CDOT', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle County Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lake Christine Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service Burn Area Emergency Response', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Barron', 'PERSON'), ('Kris Widlak', 'PERSON'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Elise Thatcher', 'PERSON'), ('NWS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BAER', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thatcher', 'PERSON'), ('Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('David Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('Eagle Valle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Geological Survey', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""White River National Forest Supervisor 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('The National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Birch Barron', 'PERSON')"
As_Grizzly_Creek_Fire_threatens_Dotsero_residents__Eagle_Valley_Enterprise_CO___August_20_2020.txt,"('Mi Charco', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Garfield County', 'LOCATION'), ('Interstate 70', 'LOCATION'), ('EC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Laura Rascn', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Stephanie Chavez', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Dotsero', 'LOCATION'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chavez', 'PERSON'), ('Mi Charco', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Battle Mountain High School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle Valle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle County PIO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mi Salud', 'LOCATION'), ('Rascn', 'PERSON'), ('Cassandra Armas', 'PERSON')"
As_wildfires_rage_Biden_meets_with_Western__Lamar_Ledger_CO___June_30_2021.txt,"('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Pacific Northwest', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Pikes Peak Visitors Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('White House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('White House', 'LOCATION'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Christopher French', 'PERSON'), ('Anita Dunn', 'PERSON'), ('Interior Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Firefighting Air Corps Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gina McCarthy', 'PERSON'), ('Federal Emergency Management Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION')"
At Loveland event Gov Polis calls on all voices to join sust.txt,"('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Wade Troxell', 'PERSON'), ('Jonathan Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Clean Energy Action', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Zero Emission Vehicle Program', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Public Utilities Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('EnergySmart', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Deb Gardner', 'PERSON'), ('Advisory Committee on Environmental Sustainability', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Platte River Power Authority', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('Broomfield', 'PERSON'), ('Office of Emergency Management for Larimer County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Volkswagen', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Darla Arians', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield', 'LOCATION'), ('Lori Hodges', 'PERSON')"
At_least_26_homes_lost_as_Cal-Wood_fire_still_at_8__Colorado_Daily_Boulder_CO___October_18_2020.txt,"('Mountain Ridge Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Jane Brautigam', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('FEMA', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Boulder County 's North Broadway Complex"", 'LOCATION'), ('Cal-Wood Education Center', 'LOCATION'), ('Jamestown', 'LOCATION'), ('White Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Hall Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Anne U', 'PERSON'), ('County Road 87', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nelson Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Wagner', 'PERSON'), ('Cal-Wood', 'LOCATION'), ('Pella Crossing', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Altona', 'LOCATION'), ('Fourmile Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grant', 'PERSON'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('N. Broadway', 'LOCATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Gold Hill', 'LOCATION'), ('Lee Hill Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Wagner', 'PERSON'), ('North Foothills Highway', 'LOCATION'), ('Lagerman Agricultural Preserve', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Valley School District', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Boulder County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Foothills Ranch Drive', 'LOCATION'), ('Heil Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Heil Valley Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Olde Stage Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION')"
Avoiding_disaster_How_to_mitigate_the_risk_of__Summit_Daily_News_CO___July_1_2021.txt,"('Dillon Ranger District', 'PERSON'), ('Summit Fire & EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lipsher', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('White & Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Steve Lipsher', 'PERSON'), ('Explore Breckenridge & Summit County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Breckenridge', 'LOCATION'), ('White & Blue Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jim Keating', 'PERSON')"
A_lot_of_structures_under_threat_Cameron_Peak__Colorado_Sun_The_CO___September_7_2020.txt,"('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('High Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Front Range', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chambers Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('Dakotas.The Associated Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Old Fall River', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak - Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trail Ridge', 'LOCATION'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('Oregon', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'PERSON'), ('Buckhorn Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Jesse Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Greeley', 'LOCATION')"
A_pretty_intense_firefight_Assessing_the_battle__Craig_Daily_Press_CO___August_21_2020.txt,"('Scott Condon', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('Hanging Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Bair Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Dotsero', 'PERSON'), ('Craig Daily Pre', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lookout Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('No Name Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Cascade', 'LOCATION'), ('Kempel', 'PERSON'), ('Montana', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Lookout Park', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Wayne Patterson', 'PERSON'), ('Fitzwilliams', 'PERSON'), ('Patterson', 'PERSON'), ('8th Street', 'LOCATION'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Scott Fitzwilliams', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Craig Daily Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Incident Command Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bair Ranch', 'PERSON'), ('Joe Kempel', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Times Firefighters', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Goolsby', 'PERSON')"
Basalt_beefs_up_fire-wise_regulations_as_part_of__Aspen_Times_The_CO___August_26_2020.txt,"('Lake Christine Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Mele', 'PERSON'), ('Basalt', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Ryan Mahoney', 'PERSON'), ('Mahoney', 'PERSON'), ('Town Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mele', 'PERSON')"
Beetles_are_on_the_move_in_Aspen-area_forests__Denver_Post_The_CO___March_3_2021__p7A.txt,"('Adam McCurdy', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lake Christine', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aspen Center for Environmental Studies', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pitkin County', 'LOCATION'), ('Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('Elk Mountains', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan West', 'PERSON'), ('Gunnison County', 'LOCATION'), ('McCurdy', 'PERSON'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION')"
Before_a_prescribed_burn_comes_a_ton_of_planning__Durango_Herald_The_CO___June_9_2021.txt,"('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Springs Road', 'LOCATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Arizona', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brad Pietruszka', 'PERSON'), ('urkey Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Montana', 'LOCATION'), ('Pagosa Lakes', 'LOCATION'), ('Fred Ellis', 'PERSON'), ('Archuleta County', 'LOCATION'), ('Patrick Armijo', 'PERSON'), ('Brockover', 'LOCATION'), ('Pagosa Ranger District', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gambel', 'PERSON'), ('Ellis', 'PERSON'), ('Flagstaff', 'LOCATION'), ('Durang', 'PERSON'), ('Pietruszka', 'PERSON'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION')"
Belden_set_to_take_over_as_new_KCC_sheriff_with__Burlington_Record_CO___April_15_2021.txt,"('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('KCC Commissioners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kit Carson County', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Belden', 'PERSON'), ('Rick Mauch', 'PERSON'), ('Tom Ridnour', 'PERSON'), ('Ridnour', 'PERSON'), ('KCC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wick', 'PERSON'), ('John Wick', 'PERSON')"
Big_questions_loom_after_inspection_of_Grizzly__Sky-Hi_News_Granby_CO___March_2_2021.txt,"('Scott Condon', 'PERSON'), ('Hunter', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Basalt Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon Restoration Alliance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lake Christine Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Steve Hunter', 'PERSON'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BAER', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roaring Fork Conservancy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('David Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Roaring Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Geological Survey', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elizabeth Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Christina Medved', 'PERSON')"
Black Hills Energy is gearing up to launch its western Puebl.txt,"('Southern Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Puebl Black Hills Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pueblo County', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Public Utilities Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Vance Crocker , Black Hills Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Crocker', 'PERSON'), ('Ready Electric Vehicle Program', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Vestas', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Black Hills', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Black Hills', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Peak View', 'PERSON'), ('Huerfano County', 'LOCATION'), ('Bush Ranch Two', 'PERSON'), ('Black Hills Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pueblo', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Hills', 'LOCATION')"
BLMs new resource management plan for North Fork and region.txt,"('Delta', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Scott Braden', 'PERSON'), ('BLM', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mesa', 'LOCATION'), ('( Michael ) Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('Gunnison', 'LOCATION'), ('NEPA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('RMP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ouray', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Western Slope Conservation Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('Uncompahgre Field Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('North Fork', 'LOCATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kerry Donovan', 'PERSON'), ('Gunnison Gorge', 'LOCATION'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('San Miguel', 'LOCATION'), ('FLPMA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gunnison', 'PERSON'), ('Julie McCluskey', 'PERSON'), ('Wilderness Society and Wilderness Workshop', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('WSCC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Montrose', 'LOCATION')"
Boebert introduces bill to pay for logging raise timber reve.txt,"('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Arizona', 'LOCATION'), ('Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Boebert', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Durango Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('American Loggers Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ken Buck', 'PERSON'), ('Rio Blanco', 'LOCATION'), ('Lauren Boebert', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Off-Highway Vehicle Coalition', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House Natural Resources Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Reserve Revenue Areas', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Garfield', 'LOCATION'), ('Doug Lamborn', 'PERSON'), ('Montrose', 'LOCATION')"
Boulder adjusting climate approach.txt,"('Brett KenCairn', 'PERSON'), ('Mark Wallach', 'PERSON'), ('Gichon', 'PERSON'), ('Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Lauren Tremblay', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder Valley Comprehensive Plan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jonathan Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Weaver', 'PERSON'), ('Alice Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Tremblay', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Public Utilities Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sam Weaver', 'PERSON'), ('City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Oxfam', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United States', 'LOCATION'), ('ICLEI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Yael Gichon', 'PERSON'), ('KenCairn', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Boulder County cleantech companies see demand increasing aft.txt,"('Riverstone Holdings LLC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Front Range', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('NREL', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Peter Lilienthal', 'PERSON'), ('Writz', 'PERSON'), ('Tucci', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Uplight', 'LOCATION'), ('Lilienthal', 'PERSON'), ('El Mallakh', 'PERSON'), ('Solid Power', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Renewable Energy Laboratory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Office of Economic Development and International Trade', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('DOE', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Exxon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rob Writz', 'PERSON'), ('White House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('McKenna', 'PERSON'), ('Helen El Mallakh', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Decarbonization Plus Acquisition Corp. III', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Louisvillebased Solid Power', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('El Mallakh', 'LOCATION'), ('Angela Tucci', 'PERSON'), ('AMP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University of Colorado Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('The Department of Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Homer Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Special Purpose Acquisition Company', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Northern Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Massachusetts', 'LOCATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Underwriters Laboratories', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('AMP Robotics', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Will McKenna', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Cleantech Industries Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Advanced Industries Grant Program', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('ElectraSteel Inc.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield', 'LOCATION'), ('SPAC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Uplight', 'PERSON')"
Boulder Countys native bee species thrive in disturbed.txt,"('Boulder County Parks', 'LOCATION'), ('University of Colorado Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Adrian Carper', 'PERSON'), ('Carper', 'PERSON'), ('Stefan Reinold', 'PERSON'), ('Davis', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County Open Space', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Seth Davis', 'PERSON')"
Boulder ending contract with director of climate initiatives.txt,"('Steve Catanach', 'PERSON'), ('Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Huntley', 'PERSON'), ('Emily Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sarah Huntley', 'PERSON'), ('Chris Meschuk', 'PERSON'), ('Communications', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('Jonathan Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Catanach', 'PERSON')"
Boulder finding success in climate initiatives.txt,"('Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Housing Partners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Equitable', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lauren Tremblay', 'PERSON'), ('Emily Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('Gateway Park Fun Center', 'LOCATION'), ('Tim Beal', 'PERSON'), ('North Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('GRID Alternatives Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beal', 'PERSON'), ('Jonathan Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder Municipal Airport', 'LOCATION')"
Boulder mayors conversation calls for action against climate.txt,"('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Vadim Uzdensky', 'PERSON'), ('Fairview High School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Young', 'PERSON'), ('Weaver', 'PERSON'), ('Franklyn', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Clean Energy Action', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sam Weaver', 'PERSON'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Junie Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('Ponderosa Moble Home Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Michelle Aguayo', 'PERSON'), ('Microgrid News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West Boulder Senior Center', 'LOCATION'), ('University Colorado Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lili Francklyn', 'PERSON'), ('Uzdensky', 'PERSON'), ('Uzensky', 'PERSON'), ('Mary Young', 'PERSON'), ('Local Clean Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Xcel', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leslie Glustrom', 'PERSON')"
Boulder recognized by nonprofit for climate action reporting.txt,"('Katie Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Lauren Tremblay', 'PERSON'), ('North America', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Measures', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Boulder rethinking climate approach.txt,"('Brett KenCairn', 'PERSON'), ('Koehn', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('KenCairn', 'PERSON'), ('Jonathan Koehn', 'PERSON')"
Boulder schedules forum to kick off neighborhood climate.txt,"('David Ensign', 'PERSON'), ('Vasatka', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Emily Sandoval', 'PERSON'), ('ANCA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elizabeth Vasatka', 'PERSON'), ('Ensign', 'PERSON')"
Boulder_County_braces_for_another_intense_wildfire__FOX_31_KDVR_Denver_CO___May_27_2021.txt,"('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County Wildfire Partners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sherwood Gulch', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Ralph Price Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder Valley Conservation District', 'LOCATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('Hall Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Ron Stewart', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Shanahan Ridge', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County Calwood', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rabbit Mountain', 'LOCATION'), (""Boulder Fire Department 's Wildland Division"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wildfire Home Assessment Program', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Longmont The City', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Ranger District', 'LOCATION'), ('Button Rock Preserve', 'LOCATION'), ('Nederland', 'LOCATION'), ('City Utilities Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wood', 'PERSON'), ('Gold Hill', 'LOCATION'), ('Colo.', 'LOCATION'), ('Gold Hill Fire District', 'LOCATION'), ('Mountain Parks', 'LOCATION'), ('CSFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hall Ranch', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Boulder County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Calwood', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Creek Watershed', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Boulder_County_evacuees_hopeful_after_weather__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_19_2020.txt,"('Burt', 'PERSON'), ('Alhadeff', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Ward', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Jamestown', 'LOCATION'), ('Island Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Nanby Wentzel', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Durango Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mary Shinn Linda Burt', 'PERSON'), ('Rustic Moose', 'PERSON'), ('Max Savich', 'PERSON'), ('Savich', 'PERSON'), ('Ice Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Leslie James', 'PERSON'), ('South Mineral Creek Campground', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Creek Lodge', 'LOCATION'), ('Left Hand Canyon Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nederland', 'LOCATION'), ('Cara Judea Alhadeff', 'PERSON'), ('Red Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wentzel', 'PERSON'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Left Hand Canyon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jesse Snouwaert', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Ice Lake Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Office of Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Boulder_County_Sheriffs_Office_Calwood_Fires__Colorado_Daily_Boulder_CO___February_10_2021.txt,"(""Boulder County Sheriff 's Office Communications Center"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cal-Wood Education Center off County Road 87', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Ward', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Calwo', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County Communications Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Gilpin County', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Incident Management Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Longmont Humane Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Daily ( Boulder', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder Emergency Operations Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco Firearms and Explosives', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County Fairgrounds', 'LOCATION'), ('Red Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kelsey Hammon', 'PERSON'), ('Humane Society of Boulder Valley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), (""Boulder County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Calwood', 'LOCATION'), ('Communications Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Office of Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Bracing_for_more_big_wildfires_Colorado_leaders__Lamar_Ledger_CO___April_8_2021.txt,"('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lamar Ledg', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Jacque Buchanan', 'PERSON'), ('Mike Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Buchanan', 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lamar Le', 'PERSON')"
Breckenridge protest symbolizes lives lost to climate change.txt,"('Ugne Kaselas', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Whinston', 'PERSON'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Natural Resources Defense Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Julia Whinston', 'PERSON'), ('Summit Sustainability Club', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lithuania', 'LOCATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Kaselas', 'PERSON'), ('Andy Schoeneman', 'PERSON'), ('Breckenridge', 'LOCATION'), ('Schoeneman', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Broomfield approves greenhouse gas reduction goals.txt,"('Ward', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Groom', 'PERSON'), ('University Of Colorado Denver', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nissan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Health and Human Services Building', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Advisory Committee on Environmental Sustainability', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield', 'PERSON'), ('Catherine Drumheller', 'PERSON'), ('Laurie Anderson', 'PERSON'), ('Broomfield', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Stan Jezierski', 'PERSON'), ('Heun', 'PERSON'), ('Guyleen Castriotta', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Energy Performance Contracting', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield City Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aaron Heun', 'PERSON'), ('Patrick Quinn', 'PERSON'), ('Kimberly Groom', 'PERSON'), ('ACES', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield', 'LOCATION'), ('United States', 'LOCATION')"
Bull Mountain development plan finds new life.txt,"('Bull Mountain', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BLM', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Natasha Leger', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Center for Biological Diversity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leger', 'PERSON'), ('CHC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Western Slope Conservation Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('Tanya Henderson', 'PERSON'), ('Stephanie Connolly', 'PERSON'), ('Bull Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('North Fork Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('WSCC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Healthy Community', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Southwest District', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Burned_battered_and_buoyant_Stories_from_2020s__Eagle_Valley_Enterprise_CO___December_22_2020.txt,"('Harry Potter', 'PERSON'), ('Jim Skoronsky', 'PERSON'), ('Burne', 'PERSON'), ('Hanging Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Arizona', 'LOCATION'), ('Civilian Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bill Stephens', 'PERSON'), ('Crooked Creek Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Stephens', 'PERSON'), ('Great Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Mary Stephens', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Post Independent', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('Minnesota', 'LOCATION'), ('Skoronsky', 'PERSON'), ('Eagle County Colorado State University Extension Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cottonwood Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Schrenker', 'PERSON'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Googling Skoronsky', 'PERSON'), ('Fitzwilliams', 'PERSON'), ('Albus Dumbledore', 'PERSON'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Dotsero', 'LOCATION'), ('Halvorson', 'PERSON'), ('Scott Fitzwilliams', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Marcia Gilles', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado River Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Hanging Lake', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denyse Schrenker', 'PERSON'), ('Eagle Valle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ryan Halvorson', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'LOCATION'), ('Coffee Pot Spring', 'LOCATION'), ('Hanging Lake Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Post Independent', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sweetwater', 'LOCATION'), ('Giles', 'PERSON')"
CalWood_fire_update_At_least_20_homes_lost_as__Daily_Record_The_Caon_City_CO___October_18_2020.txt,"('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Climate Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jamestown', 'LOCATION'), ('National Weather Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon Drive', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Nelson Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Wagner', 'PERSON'), ('LaFollete', 'PERSON'), ('Joe LaFollete', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Russ Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County Fairgrounds', 'LOCATION'), ('Caon City', 'LOCATION'), ('Longmont', 'LOCATION'), ('Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('N. Broadway', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Wagner', 'PERSON'), (""Boulder County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Heil Valley Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('North Broadway Complex', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Shelly Bradbury Courtney Walsh', 'PERSON')"
CalWood_Lefthand_Canyon_fires_Containment_grows__Daily_Camera_The_Boulder_CO___October_21_2020.txt,"('Pelle', 'PERSON'), ('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Brooklyn Dance Between Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Derek Williams', 'PERSON'), ('USDA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Josh Shroyer', 'PERSON'), ('Jamestown', 'LOCATION'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Ranger Angie Gee', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Joe Pelle', 'PERSON'), ('Lefthand Canyon Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_Fire_continues_to_grow_slowly___Estes_Park_Trail-Gazette_CO___September_3_2020.txt,"('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Crown Point Road', 'LOCATION'), ('NIMO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Manhattan Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Deadman Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Long Draw Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Laramie River Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Portland', 'LOCATION'), ('Green Ridge', 'LOCATION'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Portland National Incident Management Organization', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Neota Wilderness', 'LOCATION'), ('Walden', 'LOCATION'), ('Pingree Park Road', 'LOCATION'), ('RMIM Team Black', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United States Forest Service Wildand Fire Air Quality Response', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Cameron_Peak_Fire_East_Troublesome_Fire_cooled_by__Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___October_27_2020.txt,"('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), (""Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Byrd', 'PERSON'), ('Masonville', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Dallas', 'PERSON'), ('Joe Sean Kennedy', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak Fire The Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mullen', 'PERSON'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Katie Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('KOA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rob Allen', 'PERSON'), ('Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Glen Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Pacific Northwest Area Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brett Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Stove Prairie School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Red Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('Noel Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Canyon Lakes', 'LOCATION'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('County Road 27', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_fire_explodes_into_Colorados_largest__Colorado_Sun_The_CO___October_14_2020.txt,"('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Horsetooth Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Masonville', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Dallas', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Lory State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Jesse Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook Live', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Horsetooth Mountain Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Lucy Hag', 'PERSON'), ('Dallas', 'LOCATION'), ('Broomfield', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_fire_flares_up_again_Fort_Carson__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_14_2020.txt,"('Security', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wescott', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Lory State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Carson', 'PERSON'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'LOCATION'), ('Oregon', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Parks and Wildlife', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roosevelt', 'LOCATION'), ('Carso', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Palmer Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen Haven', 'PERSON'), ('Cimarron Hills', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado 115', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Palisade', 'LOCATION'), ('Pine Gulch', 'PERSON'), ('Parris', 'PERSON'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eric Parris', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Carson', 'LOCATION'), ('El Paso County Wildland', 'LOCATION'), ('Jered Kramer', 'PERSON'), ('Army', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs Utilities', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen', 'PERSON')"
Cameron_Peak_Fire_growth_halted_by_snow_and_cold__Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___September_9_2020.txt,"('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Brad Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Chuck Russell', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Valley Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tom Barter', 'PERSON'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Katie Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('LCSO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Australia', 'LOCATION'), ('Russell', 'PERSON'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Monument Gulch Area', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Monument Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Portland National Incident Management Organization', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service Canyon Lakes', 'LOCATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Jon', 'PERSON'), ('Poudre Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen Haven', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_fire_largest_in_state_history_grows__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_15_2020.txt,"('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lawn Lake Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt', 'LOCATION'), ('Lory State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Carson', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Big Horn Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Brandy Gill', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_fire_now_largest_in_Colorado_history__Greeley_Tribune_CO___October_15_2020.txt,"('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Front Range', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('County Road 41', 'LOCATION'), ('Masonville', 'LOCATION'), ('Otter Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Overhill Drive', 'LOCATION'), ('Deadman', 'LOCATION'), ('Bellaire Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Manhattan Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Dallas', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Estes Park Power and Communications', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Stratton Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Signal Peak', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lory State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Renan Casagrande', 'PERSON'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'LOCATION'), ('Casagrande', 'PERSON'), ('Drake', 'PERSON'), ('Wayne Patterson', 'PERSON'), ('Milner Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Palisade Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Redstone Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Patterson', 'PERSON'), ('Mountain Campus', 'LOCATION'), ('Cairns', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Arapahoe', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen Haven', 'PERSON'), ('Brazil', 'LOCATION'), ('Cairns', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Park', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Buckhorn', 'LOCATION'), ('Comanche Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Stove Prairie', 'LOCATION'), ('Western Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Horsetooth Mountain Park', 'LOCATION'), ('County Road 27', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen', 'PERSON'), ('Pingree Park Road', 'LOCATION'), ('CSU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CSU Mountain Campus', 'LOCATION'), ('Glen Haven', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Cass Cairns', 'PERSON')"
Cameron_Peak_fire_now_largest_in_state_history__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_15_2020.txt,"('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lawn Lake Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Hayman', 'PERSON'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt', 'LOCATION'), ('Lory State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Carson', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Big Horn Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Brandy Gill', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION')"
Cameron_Peak_Fire_reaches_5_containment_along__Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___September_2_2020.txt,"('Boyd Lebeda', 'PERSON'), ('Justin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Canyon Lakes', 'LOCATION'), ('Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), (""Larimer County Sheriff 's Office"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United States Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Incident Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tom Barter', 'PERSON'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak Fire Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Katie Donahue', 'PERSON'), ('Lebeda', 'PERSON')"
CDOT_officials_brace_for_debris_danger_from_burn__Vail_Daily_CO___April_2_2021.txt,"('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('CDOT', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Highway 13', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Silverthorne', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountains', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Highway 40', 'LOCATION'), ('Grizzly Creek Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cottonwood Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Elise Thatcher', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thatcher', 'PERSON'), ('Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('David Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('CDOT Northwest Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('USFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Crooked Creek Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('USFS Burned Area Emergency Response', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Craig', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Highway 9', 'LOCATION')"
Chew on this Goats mow down fire danger in La Plata County.txt,"('Bangert', 'PERSON'), ('Lewis', 'LOCATION'), ('Southwest Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Gambel', 'LOCATION'), ('Edgemont Highlands Community Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rx Grazing Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Sarah Bangert', 'PERSON'), ('Ron Duvall', 'PERSON'), ('La Plata County', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION'), ('Pioneer Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Gambel', 'PERSON'), ('Duvall', 'PERSON'), ('Edgemont Highlands', 'LOCATION'), ('Red Canyon Trail', 'LOCATION'), ('Florida Road ( County Road', 'LOCATION')"
Civilian_Conservation_Corps_shaped_Colorado._Joe__Journal-Advocate_Sterling_CO___June_1_2021.txt,"('Scott Segerstrom', 'PERSON'), ('Kevin Heiner', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Civilian Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roosevelt', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Banks', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Youth Corps Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Salida', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Civilian Climate Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Steamboat Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Ohio', 'LOCATION'), ('Red Rocks Park', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pearson', 'PERSON'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""P. O'Connell Pearson"", 'PERSON'), ('White House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lafayette', 'LOCATION'), ('Civilian Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('CCC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Red Rocks', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION'), ('Jo e - Jo urnal-Advo', 'PERSON'), ('Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain Youth Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John McCain', 'PERSON'), ('Ryan Banks', 'PERSON'), ('Civilian Conservation Corps Helped Save America', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CO ) Justin Wing', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Elbert', 'LOCATION'), ('Marcy Kaptur', 'PERSON'), ('Southwest Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Morrison', 'LOCATION')"
Climate Action Collaborative A song of ice and fire.txt,"('Beaver Creek', 'PERSON'), ('Royal Elk Glade', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Vail Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle River Watershed Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walking Mountains Science Center', 'LOCATION'), ('Avon', 'LOCATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Claire Kantor', 'PERSON'), ('Royal Elk Glade', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Forest Management Plan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beaver Creek', 'LOCATION')"
Climate change politics shifting  More candidates are accept.txt,"('Chelsie Miera', 'PERSON'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Bob Rankin', 'PERSON'), ('Gardner', 'PERSON'), ('Hanlon', 'PERSON'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Democratic Party', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rankin', 'PERSON'), ('Miera', 'PERSON'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lauren Boebert', 'PERSON'), ('Pew Research Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West Slope Colorado Oil & Gas Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Flanigan', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Cory Gardner', 'PERSON'), ('Palisade High School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Liliana Flanigan', 'PERSON'), ('Karl Hanlon', 'PERSON'), ('Jackson County', 'LOCATION'), ('Yuma Republican', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Climate expert to Vail Valley leaders Nowhere close to the n.txt,"('Davies', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Franklin Delano Roosevelt', 'PERSON'), ('Nazi', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United States', 'LOCATION'), ('Vail Resorts', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Avon', 'LOCATION'), ('Winston Churchill', 'PERSON'), ('Great Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('Battle Mountain High School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('Robert Davies', 'PERSON'), ('Vail', 'LOCATION')"
Climate_Action_Collaborative_Opportunities_for__Vail_Daily_CO___June_10_2020.txt,"('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Knapp Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle County Greenhouse Gas Inventory Report', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kim Langmaid', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Parks and Wildlife', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walking Mountains Science Center', 'LOCATION'), ('Hoop House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kim Lang', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Town Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jackson Hole', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Local Affairs', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eagle Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Climate Actio n Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Climate_change_is_a_big_reason_for_fires__Delta_County_Independent_CO___October_14_2020.txt,"('Brad', 'PERSON'), ('Redding', 'LOCATION'), ('LA', 'LOCATION'), ('Jay Inslee', 'PERSON'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('North America', 'LOCATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('DCI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Santa Cruz', 'LOCATION'), ('Park Williams', 'PERSON'), (""Columbia University 's Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory"", 'ORGANIZATION')"
Climate_change_is_helping_to_fuel__FOX_31_KDVR_Denver_CO___October_22_2020.txt,"('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('StevensRumann', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rob Low', 'PERSON'), ('Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Climate Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Stevens-Rumann', 'PERSON'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('FORT COLLINS', 'LOCATION'), ('Colo.', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Camille Stevens-Rumann', 'PERSON'), ('Russ Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Climate_change_is_making_Rocky_Mountain__Durango_Herald_The_CO___June_18_2021.txt,"('U.S. West', 'LOCATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Herald', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Medieval Climate Anomaly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wyoming', 'LOCATION'), ('Continental', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Rockies', 'LOCATION'), ('Philip Higuera', 'PERSON'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountains', 'LOCATION'), ('University of Wyoming', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Research', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bryan Shuman', 'PERSON'), ('University of Montana', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('The University of Montana', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Northern Hemisphere', 'LOCATION'), ('Durang', 'PERSON'), ('Kyra Wolf', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain', 'LOCATION')"
Coalition promotes Rockies motherlode of natural gas as sour.txt,"('Moffat', 'PERSON'), ('Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Duane Zavadil', 'PERSON'), ('Enverus', 'LOCATION'), ('Bernadette Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('West Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('Coos Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Mesa', 'LOCATION'), ('Front Range', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Associated Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('Kolbenschlag', 'PERSON'), ('Denver-Julesburg Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Jordan Cove', 'LOCATION'), ('Andrew Browning', 'PERSON'), ('Heatheryn Higgins', 'PERSON'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Canada', 'LOCATION'), ('Garfield County', 'LOCATION'), ('Piceance Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Rio Blanco', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Energy Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Hopkins University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Bill Barrett Corp.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rockies', 'LOCATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('West Coast', 'LOCATION'), (""Utah Governor 's Office of Energy Development"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Uintah Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Paonia', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Potential Gas Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tribal Nations Natural Gas Initiative', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pete Kolbenschlag', 'PERSON'), ('Ore.', 'LOCATION'), ('Federal Energy Regulatory Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Garfield', 'PERSON'), ('North American West Coast', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Energy Information Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wyoming Energy Authority', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Oregon', 'LOCATION'), ('Browning', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Pembina', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Baja California', 'LOCATION'), ('Zavadil', 'PERSON'), ('Massachusetts Institute of Technology', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Energy Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('San Juan Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Permian Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('West Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Pembina Pipeline Corp.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tom Jankovsky', 'PERSON'), ('West Slope Colorado Oil and Gas Conservation Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rockies', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Jankovsky', 'PERSON'), ('Western States', 'LOCATION'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('Bloomberg', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department of Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION')"
Colo.s_prison_firefighters_have_path_to_permanent__Denver_Post_The_CO___April_20_2021__p4A.txt,"('Dylan Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Caon City', 'LOCATION'), ('Dean Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department of Corrections', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Buena Vista', 'LOCATION')"
Coloradans_Urged_to_Reduce_Wildfire_Risk_While__Estes_Park_Trail-Gazette_CO___May_2_2020.txt,"('Jennifer Eberlien', 'PERSON'), ('Mike Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Region', 'LOCATION'), ('Office of Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Department of Natural Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('USDA Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Fire Protection Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Warner College of Natural Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('DFPC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('CSFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Firewise USA', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado and Summit officials plan for wildfire season.txt,"('Colorado Army National Guard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('State Wildland Inmate Fire Team', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brian Bovaird', 'PERSON'), ('Jeff Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention & Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Black Hawk', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lipsher', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Corrections', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Summit Board of County Commissioners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('FitzSimons', 'PERSON'), ('Western Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Steve Lipsher', 'PERSON'), ('Jaime FitzSimons', 'PERSON'), ('United States', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado College achieves decadelong goal of carbon neutrali.txt,"('David Amster-Olszewski', 'PERSON'), ('Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Tutt Library', 'LOCATION'), ('Calhan', 'LOCATION'), ('Ethan Greenberg', 'PERSON'), ('Sun Share Community Solar', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Amster-Olszewski', 'PERSON'), ('AmsterOlszewski', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Ian Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Paige Shetty', 'PERSON'), ('Exxon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Shell', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Office of Sustainability', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Amy Trinidad', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lily Weissgold', 'PERSON'), (""American College & University Presidents ' Climate Commitment"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weissgold', 'PERSON'), ('Dick Celeste', 'PERSON'), ('Mobil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Board of Trustees', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Colorado Springs Utilities ' Green Power"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Steve Payne', 'PERSON'), ('Chevron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rocky Mountain', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado drought conditions still critical for Western Slope.txt,"('Karl Wetlaufer', 'PERSON'), ('Bollinger', 'PERSON'), ('USDA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('USDA Farm Service Agency Disaster Assistance Programs', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Western Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Stagecoach Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('USDA Rural Development', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Water Availability Task Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Becky Bollinger', 'PERSON'), ('Denver Water', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Steamboat Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Yampa River', 'LOCATION'), ('Upper Colorado River Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Natural Resources Conservation Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Marianne Goodland Section', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Yampa', 'LOCATION'), ('Eastern Plains', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan Mountains', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Politics', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dillon Reservoir', 'LOCATION'), ('Wetlaufer', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Water Conservation Board', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('San Miguel', 'LOCATION'), ('Megan Holcomb', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('South Platte', 'LOCATION'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION'), ('Holcomb', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Routt', 'LOCATION'), ('Western Slope', 'LOCATION'), ('Routt County', 'LOCATION'), ('Montrose', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado far from meeting emissionsreduction goals report sa.txt,"('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Alex Burness', 'PERSON'), ('Shelby Wieman', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'LOCATION'), ('Kyle Clark-Sutton', 'PERSON'), ('Aurora', 'LOCATION'), ('Environmental Defense Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Kelly Nordini', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Western Resource Advocates', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Energy Innovation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wieman', 'PERSON'), ('Caon City', 'LOCATION'), ('Tellinghuisen', 'PERSON'), ('Dominique Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Conservation Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Clark-Sutton', 'PERSON'), ('Stacy Tellinghuisen', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judith Kohler', 'PERSON'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('Daily Re', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('RMI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rocky Mountain Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Greenhouse', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Denver Post', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Colorado fire updates Sylvan Fire in Eagle County grows to 3.txt,"('Sylvan Lake State Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Eagle County', 'LOCATION'), ('Sylvan Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Red Table Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Conrad', 'PERSON'), ('Vosburg Pike Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Justin Conrad', 'PERSON'), ('David Boyd', 'PERSON'), ('White River National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Durango', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado governor releases final plan to reduce emissions by.txt,"('Thornton', 'PERSON'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('Winter', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Lightsource BP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Western Resource Advocates', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Public Utilities Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alex Valdez', 'PERSON'), ('Kevin Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Tellinghuisen', 'PERSON'), ('Westminster', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Oil and Gas Conservation Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Northglenn', 'LOCATION'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Evraz', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Stacy Tellinghuisen', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Pueblo', 'LOCATION'), ('United States', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado officials hold summit to get public feedback on wil.txt,"('Courtney Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lincoln Tunnel', 'LOCATION'), ('21st Century Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Safety', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Stan Hilkey', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Hilkey', 'PERSON'), ('Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('New York', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado oil and gas company aims to produce cleanest.txt,"('Bro', 'PERSON'), ('Payne Institute for Public Policy at the Colorado School of Mines', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bazilian', 'PERSON'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('Chris Romer', 'PERSON'), ('WildEarth Guardians', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Morgan Bazilian', 'PERSON'), ('North Dakota', 'LOCATION'), ('Crestone', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Blohm', 'PERSON'), ('Xcel Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Payne Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Broomfield Enterprise ( CO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John Schmidt', 'PERSON'), ('Canary Project', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jeremy Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Arapahoe', 'LOCATION'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Adams', 'PERSON'), ('Engie', 'PERSON'), ('Crestone Peak Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Firestone', 'LOCATION'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('World Bank', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Project Canary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judith Kohler', 'PERSON'), ('Weld', 'LOCATION'), ('Justin Blohm', 'PERSON'), ('Romer', 'PERSON'), ('Jason Oates', 'PERSON'), ('Taryn Weiner', 'PERSON'), ('Oates', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('ESG', 'LOCATION'), ('Xcel', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Colorado regulators give initial OK to ban on flaring of oil.txt,"('Dan Haley', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Iran', 'LOCATION'), ('Environmental Defense Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('North Dakota', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('Kelly Nordini', 'PERSON'), ('Iraq', 'LOCATION'), ('Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Oil and Gas Conservation Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Bakken', 'PERSON'), ('World Bank', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Oil and Gas Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judith Kohler', 'PERSON'), ('Permian Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Greeley Tribune', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Russia', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado regulators require zeroemission devices for oil and.txt,"('Dan Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Environmental Defense Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Carbondale Trustee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dan Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Lynn Granger', 'PERSON'), ('Joey', 'PERSON'), ('American Petroleum Industry Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Communities for Climate Action', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sara Rose Tannenbaum', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. EPA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grossman', 'PERSON'), ('Greenhouse Gas Roadmap', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Erica Sparhawk', 'PERSON'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Oil and Gas Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Obama', 'PERSON')"
Colorado voters favor public land protection.txt,"('Estes Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('University of Bristol', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Nevada', 'LOCATION'), ('Rockies Project', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Arizona', 'LOCATION'), ('New Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wyoming', 'LOCATION'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Montana', 'LOCATION'), ('Corina McKendry', 'PERSON'), ('Estes Valley Land Trust', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kris Kiser', 'PERSON'), ('Outdoor Power Equipment Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), ('Tyler Pialet', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado College State of the Rockies Project', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('National Academy of Sciences', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Idaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Christopher Lowry', 'PERSON')"
Colorado wildfire update Snow prevents growth on Cameron Pea.txt,"('Ne ws Bank , Inc.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Delmerico', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer County', 'LOCATION'), ('Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Jo urnal-Advo', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Hanlon', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Foundation Wildfire Emergency Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Brush News Tribune', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Morgan Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Mo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Brus', 'PERSON'), ('Brett Schroetlin', 'PERSON'), ('Noel Livingston', 'PERSON'), ('Ne ws Bank , Inc. Hanlon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Paul Delmerico', 'PERSON'), ('Karl Hanlon', 'PERSON'), ('Red Cross Western Wildfires Fund Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kieran Nicholson', 'PERSON'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION')"
Colorados historic wildfire season could be a sign of things.txt,"('US Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('Western U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Lewis College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Co', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Jeff Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Park', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Red , White & Blue Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Julie Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Jim Keating', 'PERSON'), ('Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Mo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('Daniels', 'PERSON'), ('Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('USFS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Summit Fire & EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Colorado 's Wildland Fire Management Section"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Phillip Daniels', 'PERSON'), ('Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('Breckenridge', 'LOCATION')"
Colorados_4_major_wildfires_raging_across_the__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___August_17_2020.txt,"('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Grand Junction', 'LOCATION'), ('High Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Glenwood Canyon', 'LOCATION'), ('Bair Ranch', 'LOCATION'), ('Chambers Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Pass', 'LOCATION'), ('Fraser', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Cernicek', 'PERSON'), ('Seekins', 'PERSON'), ('Glenwood Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Mary Cernicek', 'PERSON'), ('Grizzly Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Spring Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Coffee Pot Road', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Walden', 'LOCATION'), ('Pat Seekins', 'PERSON')"
Colorados_historic_wildfire_season_could_be_a__Vail_Daily_CO___October_29_2020.txt,"('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Estes Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Western U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Lewis College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Jeff Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Park', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Red , White & Blue Fire Protection District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Julie Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Jim Keating', 'PERSON'), ('Berino', 'PERSON'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('Daniels', 'PERSON'), ('Korb', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Mountain College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Summit Fire & EMS', 'ORGANIZATION'), (""Colorado 's Wildland Fire Management Section"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Phillip Daniels', 'PERSON'), ('FRISCO', 'LOCATION'), ('Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('Breckenridge', 'LOCATION')"
Colorados_pine_beetle_is_finally_fading._What__Journal_The_Cortez_Dolores_Mancos_CO___June_2_2021.txt,"(""Colorado State University 's Colorado Forest Restoration Institute"", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('David Sitton', 'PERSON'), ('Grand Mesa', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Gunnison', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Brett Wolk', 'PERSON'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Engelmann', 'PERSON'), ('Jo', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen Wall Wood', 'LOCATION'), ('Mancos', 'LOCATION'), ('Pitts', 'PERSON'), ('T im Kyllo', 'PERSON'), ('Kyllo', 'PERSON'), ('Sitton', 'PERSON'), ('Manco', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Sun Pests', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jason Blevins', 'PERSON'), ('Aspen', 'LOCATION'), ('Montrose Forest Products', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Molly Pitts', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado T imber Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dolores', 'PERSON'), ('Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('Rio Grande', 'LOCATION'), ('Aspen Wall Wood', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Montrose', 'LOCATION')"
Colorados_prison_firefighters_have_a_bridge_to__Lamar_Ledger_CO___April_15_2021.txt,"('Dylan Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Lamar Ledg', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Dean Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Caon City', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department of Corrections', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alexander Burness', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Buena Vista', 'LOCATION'), ('Lamar Le', 'PERSON')"
Colorado_fire_bans_How_to_check_where_you_can__Daily_Reporter-Herald_The_Loveland_CO___June_29_2021.txt,"('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Arapaho National Forest * Grand Mesa National Forest * Gunnison National Forest * Pike National Forest * Rio Grande National Forest * Roosevelt National Forest * Routt National Forest * San Isabel National Forest', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Homeland Security and Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ho', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State Parks', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BLM', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Loveland', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Mesa Verde National Park * Great Sand Dunes National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('White River National Forest National Parks Each of Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Rocky Mountain National Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Gunnison National Park Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Colorado_fire_updates_Containment_shrinks_on__Gazette_The_Colorado_Springs_CO___October_20_2020.txt,"('Delmerico', 'PERSON'), ('Grand County', 'LOCATION'), ('Clear Creek', 'LOCATION'), ('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Ward', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 'LOCATION'), ('Arapaho', 'LOCATION'), ('Jamestown', 'LOCATION'), ('San Juan National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Silverton', 'LOCATION'), ('Wyoming', 'LOCATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lake Granby', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forests', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('Big Horn Park', 'LOCATION'), ('Ward', 'LOCATION'), ('Roosevelt National Forest Containment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jamestown Containment', 'LOCATION'), ('Larimer', 'LOCATION'), ('Monte Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Division of Fire Prevention and Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Paul Delmerico', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado Springs', 'LOCATION'), ('Gilpin', 'PERSON'), ('Ice Lake Basin', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder Office of Emergency Management', 'ORGANIZATION')"
Colorado_forest_report_We_must_do_more_to__FOX_31_KDVR_Denver_CO___March_8_2021.txt,"('Matt Mauro DENVER', 'PERSON'), ('Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION')"
Colorado_looking_to_Biden_for_help__Denver_Post_The_CO___November_12_2020__p1A.txt,"('Colorado River', 'LOCATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('EPA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Department of Agriculture', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Wildlife Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Putnam', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder County', 'LOCATION'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Jones', 'PERSON'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Toor', 'PERSON'), ('John Putnam', 'PERSON'), ('Environmental Protection Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Transportation and Agriculture', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lefthand Canyon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air Quality Control Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dan Gibbs', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Energy Office', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Energy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dan', 'PERSON'), ('Department of Natural Resources', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elise Jones', 'PERSON'), ('Will Toor', 'PERSON')"
Colorado_looks_to_logging_to_help_re-balance__Colorado_Daily_Boulder_CO___December_7_2020.txt,"('Fort Collins', 'LOCATION'), ('Saratoga', 'LOCATION'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Pine Gulch', 'LOCATION'), ('Cameron Peak', 'PERSON'), ('Parshall', 'PERSON'), ('Carolina Manriquez', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University of Colorado Denver', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lester', 'PERSON'), ('U.S. Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Pittington', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado State Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Wilderness Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Grand Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('Greg Aplet', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Bureau of Land Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Oregon', 'LOCATION'), ('Diana Tomback', 'PERSON'), ('Manriquez', 'PERSON'), ('Bruce Finley', 'PERSON'), ('CO', 'LOCATION'), ('Mike Lester', 'PERSON'), ('Aplet', 'PERSON'), ('Tomback', 'PERSON'), ('Owl Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Steamboat Springs-based', 'LOCATION'), ('C.J', 'PERSON')"
Colorado_officials_hold_summit_to_get_public__Vail_Daily_CO___February_19_2021.txt,"('Courtney Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), ('Summit County', 'LOCATION'), ('Lincoln T', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('John Hickenlooper', 'PERSON'), ('Vail Daily', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('21st Century Conservation Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forest Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walsh', 'PERSON'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ('Colorado Department of Public Safety', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Michael Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('Jared Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron Peak Fire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Joe Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Polis', 'PERSON'), ('Stan Hilkey', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Neguse', 'PERSON'), ('Hilkey', 'PERSON'), ('Bennet', 'PERSON'), ('New York', 'LOCATION')"
